SVIATOSLAV BORDOVSKYI

Senior QA Automation Engineer

sbaga.github.io · sbordovski@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/sviatoslavbordovski · +48518296698 WhatsApp

SUMMARY

Senior QA Automation Engineer with 9+ years of experience specializing in Selenium, Python, Pytest, Requests, Robot Framework, Playwright, Javascript, Typescript, Appium, Postman, Swagger, Websocket-client, Jenkins, Github Actions, Azure DevOps etc. Proven track record in automating complex projects from scratch, including automation of frontend and backend services for web and mobile apps, automation of websockets, FIX API etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior QA Automation Engineer Enterprise Social Media Platform, USA

Jan 2024 - Present

- Successfully developed test automation framework **using Selenium and Python** for a top notch enterprise social media platform with 500k+ visits every day from scratch.
- Participated in leading a team of 4 Software Development Engineers automating and in developing new solutions for handling test data.
- Onboarded 2 new team members, providing guidance and support to facilitate their integration into the team
- Collaborated closely with cross functional development teams to resolve difficult issues, demonstrating problem-solving skills and effective communication.
- Achieved 85%+ tests coverage by executing more than 6000 automated tests every night and reduced time of app automation support by 1.5x by optimization of the code, removing duplicate tests etc.

Senior QA Automation Engineer / AQA Lead Langate, USA

Dec 2022 - Jan 2024

The project provides financial services

- Led the development and expansion of a comprehensive test automation framework for a high-traffic enterprise currency trading platform with 3+ millions of operations per day.
- Driving automation efforts and developing innovative solutions for test data management
- Led the onboarding of 4 new team members, providing mentorship and support to integrate them effectively into the team.
- Built more than 700+ Fix Api and GUI E2E automated tests from scratch using **Selenium and Python**.

Senior QA Automation Engineer / AQA Lead

Nov 2021 - Dec 2022

EPAM, Ukraine

As part of project work, I participated in Standard and Poors Fintech domain project: an American web platform for investors, a cross-browser web application.

- Designed and developed a robust test automation framework for an enterprise financial trading platform using **Selenium**, **Python**, **Pytest-BDD** and the **Requests library**.
- Automated end-to-end tests for both frontend (UI) and backend (APIs) systems, ensuring comprehensive coverage of critical features.
- Provided technical guidance and mentorship to junior engineers, supporting their growth and skill development in test automation.
- Reduced number of bugs by 40%.
- Related team functionality tests automation coverage was increased from 35% to 75%.
- Integrated automated test suites into the CI/CD pipeline using tools **Jenkins** and **GitLab** CI for ensuring that every code commit triggered automated testing.

Temy, United Kingdom

Project 1: car rental and selling platform. Project 2: development building platform for companies and vendors

- Successfully increased overall automated test coverage by 35%, leading to more reliable and consistent test execution across the entire application.
- Designed and implemented end-to-end automation test cases using **Selenium** and **Python**, ensuring accurate coverage of key user flows and system interactions.
- Set up and configured automation tests on **CircleCI**, integrating test execution into the continuous integration pipeline and ensuring smooth, automated test runs for each code commit.
- Automated than 1000 manual cross-browser tests, reducing the time needed for manual testing on different platforms by over 50% and time by 72% and increasing test throughput for every release cycle.

Middle Test Automation Engineer Indeema, USA

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

Several projects related to medtech, sport and IOT

- Successfully implemented the entire test automation framework from scratch on several projects, covering over 65% of the application, significantly reducing the reliance on manual testing.
- Automated critical test cases that improved the overall testing efficiency and reduced the time for regression testing by 40%.
- Managed and executed the full cycle of manual and automated testing, ensuring comprehensive coverage of both new features and regression tests.
- Effectively balanced manual and automation efforts to ensure rapid identification and resolution of defects across different environments.
- Logged and tracked critical bugs using tools like Jira, leading to quicker defect identification and resolution, which reduced production issues by 60%.

Manual Test Engineer Simplybook, Iceland

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

Online booking platform that offers full online presence solution for entrepreneurs

- Efficiently switched between two diverse projects, managing manual testing efforts while ensuring product quality and timely delivery.
- Performed comprehensive testing of product features, identifying critical defects and providing detailed feedback to development teams, resulting in faster issue resolution.
- Supported customers by addressing their requests and concerns, ensuring quick troubleshooting and resolution of user-reported issues.
- Logged and tracked critical bugs using tools like **Jira**, facilitating faster identification and resolution of defects, which **significantly reduced production issues by 44%**.
- Collaborated closely with developers and cross-functional teams to resolve defects quickly, improving the overall stability and quality of product releases.

EDUCATION

Lviv University of Trade and Economics — Master's degree in International Relations

September 2006 - June 2011

CERTIFICATIONS / TRAININGS

- Build Your Team <u>License</u>
- Management Foundations <u>License</u>
- New Manager Foundations License
- Selenium Python with Pytest and built complete framework License
- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) <u>License</u>
- Postman Crash Course Learn API Testing License
- Robot Framework crash course License
- FreeCodeCamp: Responsive Web Design <u>License</u>
- University of London Responsive Website Basics: Code with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript License
- John Hopkins University HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers License
- University of California Introduction to Web Development License

SKILLS

Tools and technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Python, Pytest, Requests, Xdist, Websocket-client, Selenium, Appium, Robot Framework, Playwright, Typescript, PyMySQL, Pyyaml, REST API, Postman, quickfix, allure reports, pytest-html.

Patterns: OOP, KISS, SOLID, POM, Facade design pattern, Factory design pattern, BDD, TDD.

Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

DevOps and Cloud Services: Jenkins, Azure Devops, GCP, Browserstack, Docker.

Testing: Unit testing, GUI automation, Backend automation, Websockets automation, Fix api automation, mobile native automation, cross browser testing.

Version Control Systems: Github, Gitlab, Circle CI.

Other Tools: Jira, ClickUp, Browserstack local, Android Studio, Pycharm, VS Code.